Akita Emmanuel

3rd Floor, TAEN Business Complex, Old Airport Junction, Jos, Nigeria.

Full Stack JavaScript Developer

Mobile number: +2348(0) 133 225 610

Email: e.akita91@gmail.com

Stackoverflow: https://stackoverflow.com/users/6465738/akita-emmanuel

Github: https://github.com/Emmynash

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/emmanuel-akita-19a807108

Summary

Highly-skilled Senior Front-end Developer leveraging JavaScript to build

responsive websites, mobile apps, and interactive features that drive business growth and improve UX. Improves and redesigns travelmaxhub User Interface (travelmaxhub.com) which leads to 36% increased on

visitors per month.

Involved in writing application level code in developing pie.ng (Payment System) to interact with APIs, RESTful Web Service using AJAX and JSON. Specialized in Reactjs, React Native and responsive design. Advanced analytical skills, in-depth knowledge of Software Development

Life Cycle (SDLC). Excellent interpersonal and communication skills

Skills

UI Concept Modeling, HTML5, XHTML, CSS3, JSON, JQuery, AJAX,
Web Technologies: RESTful Web Service, Redux, Context API, API service, Integration

Frameworks: Laravel, Angular.JS, ReactJs, ReactNative, Node.JS, graphQL, Type

Script, ES6,

Database Management System: SQL Server, MONGO DB, Mongoose, Sequelize.

Operating System: Windows, Linux

Programming Languages: C++, MySQL, Web Services

Testing Tools: Jasmine, Mocha, Chai

Others: Visual Studio Code, Postman, Github, Gitlab, Firebase

Experience

DigitalPatterns Ltd. / Junior Developer

FEBRUARY 2015 - SEPTEMBER 2016, 3 Beach Road Jos, Nigeria

- Worked on front end applications using Angular JS, and React JS.
- Spearheaded redesign of company's flagship mobile app, which increased downloads by 28% in less than 6 months
- Increased email signups 12% by creating new UI for website landing page in React
- JSON with jQuery for request data and response processing.
- Handled front end development of a Travel Management System (travelmaxhub.com) and implemented payment system using Paystack which increases customer's package subscription by 16%
- Developed responsive interface using Bootstrap and used SASS for CSS.
- Worked on React JS Virtual Dom and React Views, rendering using components which contains additional component called custom HTML tags.
- JavaScript Unit Testing (Mocha, Chai).
- Play a key role in the integration of the core resort experiences

LogicalAddress Ltd. / FullStack Developer

NOVEMBER 2016 - CURRENT, 3rd Floor TAEN Building Complex Old Airport, Opp. Former NITEL Jos.

- Served as a team leader in developing a School Information Management Software (dipsims.com) and successfully migrated the application to multi-tenancy, using Laravel and Angular JS.
- Involved in writing application level code for a payment gateway (pie.ng) to interact with APIs, Web Services using AJAX, JSON and XML.
- Communicate with clients to understand the requirement of website, boost client satisfaction by 12%.
- Gained experience in project planning, involved in writing the Project Design Document and Project Plan Document.
- Worked deep on Spring MVC framework to develop new internal web applications.
- Developed and maintained critical components of e-commerce website, including shopping cart, quick view, and checkout page, using React components
- Disciplined approach to testing and quality assurance

Education

American University of Nigeria / B.Sc Computer Science

 ${\sf MAY\,2015\,\text{-}April\,2019},\ \textbf{98\,Lamido\,Zubairu\,Way\,Yola\,Township\,bypass},$

Yola Adamawa State, Nigeria.

Selected coursework

Data structures and Algorithms, Principles of Functional Programming, Web application Development, Introductory to Computer Systems,

Distributed Systems.

nHub Nigeria / Certification in PHP, JavaScript, MySQL, C++,

FEBRUARY 2017 - MARCH 2018, 3rd Floor TAEN Building Old Airport

Junction Jos.

Web Development (JavaScript, PHP, MySQL), Mobile Development

(React Native, NodeJS)

Selected coursework